Youngtaek Oh

PhD Student, Electrical Engineering, KAIST.

Research Interest

My research interest aims to build robust recognition system for image and video understanding under limited and/or biased data. Towards this goal, I have been working on data-efficient learning techniques in image and video domain. In addition, I have interest in vision and language models, specifically for enhancing visual understanding tasks.

Email: youngtaek.oh@kaist.ac.kr

Webpage: https://ytaek-oh.github.io

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering; Co-advisors: In So Kweon and Junmo Kim	Daejeon, South Korea Sep. 2021 – Present
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) M.S. in Electrical Engineering; Advisor: In So Kweon	Daejeon, South Korea Mar. 2019 – Feb. 2021
Korea University B.S. in Electrical Engineering; GPA: 4.40/4.5	Seoul, South Korea Mar. 2015 – Feb. 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

WORK EXPERIENCE	
LG AI Research	Seoul, South Korea
Research Internship	Sep. 2023 – Present
Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)	Daejeon, South Korea
Researcher, Robotics and Computer Vision Lab.	Mar. 2021 – Aug. 2021

Publication

[J1] Empirical Study on Using Adapters for Debiased Visual Question Answering Jae Won Cho, Dawit Mureja Argaw, **Youngtaek Oh**, Dong-Jin Kim, In So Kweon • Computer Vision and Image Understanding (**CVIU**), 2023.

[C5] Self-Sufficient Framework for Continuous Sign Language Recognition

Youngjoon Jang, Youngtaek Oh, Jae Won Cho, Myungchul Kim, Dong-Jin Kim, In So Kweon, Joon Son Chung
o International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2023.

[C4] Signing Outside the Studio: Benchmarking Background Robustness for Continuous Sign Language Recognition Youngjoon Jang, Youngtaek Oh, Jae Won Cho, Dong-Jin Kim, Joon Son Chung, In So Kweon o British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2022.

[C3] DASO: Distribution-Aware Semantics-Oriented Pseudo-label for Imbalanced Semi-Supervised Learning **Youngtaek Oh**, Dong-Jin Kim, In So Kweon

o Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022.

[C2] KSL-Guide: A Large-scale Korean Sign Language Dataset Including Interrogative Sentences for Guiding the Deaf and Hard-of-Hearing

Soomin Ham, Kibaek Park, Youngjoon Jang, **Youngtaek Oh**, Seokmin Yun, Sukwon Yoon, Chang Jo Kim, Han-Mu Park, In So Kweon

o International Conference on Automatic Face and Gesture Recognition (FG), 2021.

[C1] SideGuide: A Large-scale Sidewalk Dataset for Guiding Impaired People

Kibaek Park*, Youngtaek Oh*, Soomin Ham*, Kyungdon Joo*, Hyokyoung Kim, Hyoyoung Kum, In So Kweon
∘ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2020.

Honors and Awards

Top 3% Recognition Certificates, ICASSP 2023	June 2023
2nd place in NICE Challenge (\$5000), NICE Workshop at CVPR 2023	May 2023
Finalist, Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea	Nov. 2022
Outstanding Reviewer Award, ECCV 2022	Oct. 2022
National Scholarship for Science and Engineering	Mar. 2017 - Feb. 2019

ACADEMIC SERVICE

Conference Reviewer

International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)	$2024 ext{-}Present$
Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)	$2024 ext{-}Present$
International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	$2024 ext{-}Present$
Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	$2023 ext{-}Present$
International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	$2023 ext{-}Present$
Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	$2022{-}Present$
European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)	$2022 ext{-}Present$